Curriculum vitae

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Antoine Wehenkel



173 Rue de la Verrerie, 4100 Seraing (Belgium)

+32497069146

antoine.wehenkel@gmail.com

Date of birth 28 Sep 1995 | Nationality Belgian

PERSONAL STATEMENT

"Debugging is twice as hard as writing the code in the first place. Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as possible, you are, by definition, not smart enough to debug it." Kernighan's law

Since 2013 I am a student in engineering at the University of Liège. Currently I do my 2nd year of study as a master's student at the EPFL, I specialize myself in data science.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Sep 2017-Present

Exchange student

EPFL, Lausanne (Switzerland)

Enrolled in the master in data science

Sep 2016-Present

Master in computer science and engineering

University of Liège, Liège (Belgium)

Focus in intelligent systems

Sep 2013-Jun 2016

Bachelor in engineering (major in computer science, minor in electrical engineering)

University of Liège, Liège (Belgium) *Magna Cum Laude* (16.28/20)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sep 2017-Present

Student Instructor for the course of Electronic 2

Prof. Kayal - EPFL, Lausanne (Switzerland)

Coaching of students during the course's practical sessions.

Jul 2017-Sep 2017

Student Worker

Laboratory of Immunology, University of Liège

Development of an RFID based tracking system for fish. It required to chose the right hardware components, to program micro controller (Arduino), to create a web server (Django and PostgreSQL) and a monitoring system (Python).

Jul 2016-Apr 2017

Student Researcher

University Of Liège, Liège

Work in the smart grids research lab, in collaboration with Engie. The purpose of my work was to develop optimisation algorithms applied to electric vehicle fleet integration in the electrical network.

Curriculum vitae Antoine Wehenkel

Sep 2016–Jun 2017 Stu

Student instructor for the course of Advanced Programming

Prof. Geurts - University of Liège, Liège (Belgium)

Elaboration and correction of the projects.

Sep 2016-Dec 2016

Student instructor for the course of Analysis and Design of Electrical Measuring Systems

Prof. Vanderbemden - University of Liège, Liège (Belgium)

Coaching of students during their lab sessions.

Jan 2015-Jun 2016

Student instructor for the course of Computer Organization

Prof. Boigelot - University of Liège, Liège (Belgium)

Teaching practical part of the course to first bachelor students in engineering.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

French

Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B2	B2	B2	B2	B2

English

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

Good communication skills gained during my experience as a student instructor. Over the 3 last years I also took part in many group projects and developed my ability to communicate with my classmates.

Organisational / managerial skills

Good organisational skills gained during my experience in the Robocup project and the EPFL Hyperloop team.

Digital skills

- Excellent programming skills in C, C++, Python, Matlab, Java and Scheme.
- Good knowledge in convex optimization, operating systems, computer networking, machine learning and statistics.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Honours and awards

- Physics price for outstanding student(2013)
- Physics price at belgian olympiades(2012 and 2013)

Academic grades

- First Master in Computer Engineering: **Summa Cum Laude** (2016-2017)
- Third Bachelor in Engineering Sciences: **Summa Cum Laude** (2015-2016)
- Second Bachelor in Engineering Sciences : **Cum Laude** (2014-2015)
- First Bachelor in Engineering Sciences : Magna Cum Laude (2013-2014)

Publications

An App-based Algorithmic Approach for Harvesting Local and Renewable Energy Using Electric Vehicles, A Dubois, A Wehenkel, R Fonteneau, F Olivier, D Emst - ICAART 2017